(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Live 2023
「THE DAY」
Tsunomaki Watame 7th birthday
THE DAY
角巻わため生誕祭2023
Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Celebration 2023
Na na na na...
Na na na na na na na...
今日は年に一度特別な日
Today is a special day that comes once a year
君と一緒に お祝いをしよう
Let's celebrate together with you
ケーキの上 ローソク火をつけて
Light the candles on top of the cake
おめでとう 笑顔があふれるよ
Congratulations, smiles are overflowing
生まれてきたこと それは
Being born, that is...
偶然？奇跡？かもしれない
...a coincidence? A miracle? It might be
でもせっかくなら 日々をもっと
But since we're here, let's make our days even more...
happy! enjoy! さあ歌おう
Happy! Enjoy! Now, let's sing
ふわふわ雲のわたあめ食べてみたり
Maybe eat some fluffy cloud cotton candy
魔法を使って空を飛んだり
Or fly through the sky using magic
誰かを救うヒーローになったり
Or become a hero who saves someone
なんでもできそうな気がするね
I feel like I can do anything
そんな奇跡みたいな日々を ずっと もっと
Days like a miracle, forever, even more
なんでもない日々はいじわるで
Ordinary days can be unkind
唇噛みしめる時もあるよね
There are times when we bite our lips
落ち込んでへこんでおかない顔
A face that's feeling down and discouraged
大丈夫 笑顔がこぼれるよ
It's okay, a smile will spill out
生まれてきたこと それを
The fact that I was born...
後悔しちゃうかもしれない
...I might end up regretting it
でもせっかくなら日々をもっと
But if that's the case, let's make these days...
Happiness Joyful ほら行こう！
...Happiness Joyful, hey, let's go!
小さな幸せつなぎあげて
Connecting small happiness together
世界でひとつだけの宝物
A treasure that's the only one in the world
君でいた証 抱きしめて
Hold tight to the proof that you were you
生まれてきてくれてありがとう！
Thank you for being born!
君も僕も君も一緒に
You and I and you, together
同じ時に生まれた奇跡たち
The miracles born at the same time
来年も再来年も一緒に
Next year and the year after, together
ここで笑ってお祝いしよう
Let's laugh and celebrate here
そんな奇跡みたいな日々を ずっと もっと
Days like a miracle, forever, even more
叶えたい未来へ
To the future I want to fulfill
心の準備OK？
Ready in your heart?
さあ、一歩踏み出して
Now, take a step forward
いっせーの、せ！
One, two, go!
今日も楽しんでいきましょう！
Let's have fun today as well!
夢見る羊
Dreaming Sheep
真白な羊に命が宿って
Life dwelt within a pure white sheep
目覚めたんだ この大きな世界で
And I woke up in this big world
何をしようか
What shall I do?
どこに行こうか
Where shall I go?
冒険は始まった
The adventure has begun
ふらふらな足取りで弱々しく
With wobbly steps and looking weak
声が震えてうまく鳴けない
My voice trembles and I can't bleat well
そんな自分やるせない
I can't stand myself like that
自信喪失気味です
I'm feeling a bit discouraged
でも時間は進む
But time moves forward
気持ちばかり焦る
Only my feelings are impatient
ゆっくりでいいから泣いちゃだめだよ
It's okay to take it slow, so don't cry
叶えたい未来へ
To the future I want to fulfill
心の準備OK？
Is your heart ready?
さあ、一歩踏み出して
Now, take a step forward
One Two Three!
僕は君と出会って
I met you
自信を取り戻して
And regained my confidence
ゆっくりと今 確かに歩み出した
Now, slowly and surely, I've started to walk
夢を見つけて
Finding a dream
いくつも抱きかかえて
And holding many of them tight
君と話した
The future I talked about...
未来を掴みに行こう
...with you, let's go grab it
一緒に隣歩いていこう
Let's walk alongside each other
まっすぐな羊に迷いはなくさ
A straightforward sheep has no hesitation
走り出したなら急には止まれない
Once you start running, you can't stop suddenly
周りを巻き込むそんな羊に今
To become a sheep that involves everyone...
なれる気がしたんだ
...now I feel like I can
明日を迎えたいくない日も
Even on days when I don't want to face tomorrow
藍色な朝も昼も夜も
In the indigo morning, noon, and night
半分こして食べ合って夢見よう
Let's share and eat together, and dream
このまま一緒に夜に溶けて
Melting into the night together just like this
君と出会って
I met you
自信を取り戻して
And regained my confidence
泥まみれでも
Even if covered in mud
何度も走り出した
I've started running again and again
夢を...
Dream...
夢見つけて
Find a dream
いくつも抱きかかえて
Holding many in my arms
君と話した未来を
The future I talked about with you
掴みに行こう
Let's go grab it
見たこともない
I've never seen
景色広がる世界へ
Into the world where the scenery unfolds
連れて行くよ
I'll take you there
一緒にずっと歩いていこう
Let's walk together forever
同じ未来へ
To the same future
いやー、聴いてくれてありがとうございます！
Wow, thank you for listening!
改めまして、こんばんどどど！
Once again, Good evening-dododo!
ホロライブ4期生、角巻わためです！
I'm Tsunomaki Watame from Hololive's 4th Generation!
なんと！3歳からホロライブデビューして、7歳になりました！イエーイ！
Believe it or not! I debuted in Hololive at 3, and now I'm 7! Yay!
6月6日は羊の日でもあり、わための誕生日ということで、たくさんおめでとう、ありがとうございます！
June 6th is Sheep Day and also my birthday, so thank you so much for all the "Happy Birthday"s!
もっと欲しいな、もっともっと欲しいな、おめでとう、もっと欲しい！
I want more, I want even more. More "Happy Birthday"! I want even more!
ありがとう！コメント見えてるで、ありがとうございます！
Thank you! I can see your comments! Thank you so much!
いや、1曲目はね、Happy Day to Youというわためのオリジナル曲を歌わせていただきまして、
Well, for the first song, I sang my original song "Happy Day to You",
次に「夢見る羊」歌わせていただいたけど、どうだったかな？
and next I sang "Dreaming Sheep". How was it?
どうだったかな？もうね、ドキドキ緊張してね、はあ...
How was it? I was so nervous and my heart was racing, phew...
ちゃんと踊れてたかな？歌えてたかな？はあ...
Did I dance okay? Did I sing okay? Phew...
でも、こうしてね、スクショとか、みんながいっぱい撮ってくれて、んで、
But, with everyone taking lots of screenshots and such, and...
ツイッターにね、いつものね、あのね、
on Twitter, using the usual... you know,
#角巻わため生誕祭2023 というタグをつけて
using the hashtag #角巻わため生誕祭2023,
いっぱい感想とかをね、ツイートしていただけますと、わためも後から見て、それが自信に繋がるので
if you tweet lots of your thoughts, I'll look at them later and it'll give me confidence,
ぜひバシバシと、え、投稿していただきたいなと思います。
so please post them aggressively.
なんと今日は、まだまだ歌ったり踊ったりするんだけど、重大告知もありますので、
Believe it or not, I'll still be singing and dancing today, but there's also a major announcement,
え、ぜひ楽しんでいっていただきたいなと思います。
so I hope you all enjoy it until the end.
一緒に楽しんでいきましょう！
Let's have fun together!
では、真ん中のステージに次は移動したいと思います。
Now, I'm going to move to the center stage next.
行くぞー！
Here I go!
人魚姫
Mermaid Princess
ゆらゆら出てる スパンコールの中で
In the middle of the swaying sequins
小さな泡になって 消えてしまいたい
I want to become a tiny bubble and disappear
いっそ私が 人魚姫なら
If only I were a mermaid princess
泡になって 消えてしまえるのにな
I could become a bubble and disappear
傷ついた顔 見せないために
In order to not show my hurt face
偽りの上描き 振りまいていたけれど
I was scattering layers of lies, but...
もっと私が 嘘をつければいいのに
If only I could tell more lies
信じたかったんだ
I wanted to believe
あなたが王子様だと
That you were my prince
どれだけ愛確かめ合えたのに
No matter how much we confirmed our love
悲しみの海で 溺れそうな思い 今は
Feelings like I'm drowning in a sea of sadness, now...
私はおとぎ話の 人魚姫だわ
I'm the mermaid princess from a fairy tale
プライドかけて 戦い切るまで
Risking my pride, until I fight to the end
あとどのくらい 準備はできている
How much longer? I'm already prepared
もう迷わない 後悔はしない
I won't hesitate anymore, I won't have regrets
止まることは
Stopping is...
...でも止まさない
...But I won't let it stop.
昔はもっと
Long ago, I used to
たくさんの嘘で
tell many more lies.
全て固めて
I hardened my heart
私傷つけてきた
and kept hurting myself.
君じゃなくても大丈夫だとか
Saying I'd be okay even without you,
甘かった
I was so naive.
宛名のない私を
Me, without a place to belong,
ゆらゆら人魚のように
swaying like a mermaid.
行き先決まらないまま
Without a destination in sight.
どうすればいい
What should I do?
約束したじゃない
Didn't we make a promise?
ハッピーエンドじゃないのもう
This isn't a happy ending anymore.
私は結ばれない
I won't be joined with you.
人魚姫みたい
Just like the Mermaid Princess.
信じてたんだ
I truly believed
あなたが王子様だったと
that you were my prince.
どれだけ愛を確かめあったの
How much love did we confirm together?
悲しみの海で
In a sea of sadness,
溺れそうな思い　今は
feelings that I'm drowning, right now.
私はおとぎ話の
I'm in a fairy tale...
宛名のない私を
Me, without a place to belong,
ゆらゆら人魚のように
swaying like a mermaid.
行き先決まらないまま
Without a destination in sight.
どうすればいい
What should I do?
約束したじゃない
Didn't we make a promise?
ハッピーエンドじゃないのもう
This isn't a happy ending anymore.
私は結ばれない
I won't be joined with you.
人魚姫みたい
Just like the Mermaid Princess.
Woah　生まれ落ちた罪
Woah, the sin I was born with.
生き残る罰は　私という存在
The punishment for surviving is my very existence.
一瞬のときめき
A moment's excitement,
永遠のさよなら
an eternal goodbye.
いつかは許してください
Please forgive me someday.
鯨
Whale
作詞：新藤晴一　作曲・編曲：本間昭光
Lyrics: Haruichi Shindo / Composition & Arrangement: Akimitsu Homma
止める言葉も聞かずに
Without listening to words of restraint,
陸に上がってしまった
I have stepped onto the land.
クジラの物語
A whale's story,
風が覚えてた
the wind remembered it.
新しい世界へと
Toward a brand new world,
胸躍らせたのでしょう
your heart must have danced with joy.
口笛を吹きたい
I want to whistle,
気分だったのでしょう
that must have been how you felt.
海の果ては　空に続くのに
Even though the sea's end continues into the sky.
星に一番近い　この丘から
From this hill closest to the stars,
何を見てたの
what were you looking at?
Woah　大人になる罪
Woah, the sin of becoming an adult.
更けていく罰は　私という存在
The punishment that deepens is my very existence.
一瞬のきらめき
A moment's sparkle,
永遠の空白
an eternal blank.
言われない運命ね
It's an unspoken fate, isn't it?
身動きできない
I cannot even move.
クジラが絶望して
A whale fell into despair
捨てていったこの場所で
in this place that was abandoned,
私は生きている
and I am living here.
やりきれなくなるわ
I can't take it anymore.
優しくしないで
Please, don't be kind to me.
どこに触れ合わしたって
No matter where we touch
私の指先はひどく
My fingertips are terribly
切り裂かれるの
torn apart
出会ったのも罪
Meeting you was a sin
恋したのも罰という存在
Loving you is a punishment
胸を締め付ける
Tightening my chest
狂おしい気付かないで
Don't notice how mad it is
私にください痛いほどいいの
Give it to me, even if it hurts
気持ち裏腹で意地悪な私
My feelings are the opposite, I'm being mean
嫉妬隠せない惨めな私
I can't hide my jealousy, I'm miserable
隣の恋人妬んでる私
I'm jealous of the lovers next to me
自分愛せない私
I can't love myself
大きな海に抱かれてみたいのよ
I want to be embraced by the vast sea
時折水面に顔を覗かせて
Occasionally peeking my face above the water
月を眺めて歌を歌う
Gazing at the moon and singing a song
傷付いた鯨と一緒に
Together with the wounded whale
覚えておいてね私のことを
Please remember me
空まで届くの
Reaching up to the sky
愛した真実無くした事実
The truth of having loved, the fact of loss
ささやかな落日
A modest sunset
生まれ落ちた罪
The sin of being born
生き残る罰という存在
The existence of survival as a punishment
一瞬のときめき永遠のサヨナラ
A moment's fluttering, an eternal farewell
ママ許されないのかな
Mama, will I not be forgiven?
伸ばす手はどこへ
Where is my reaching hand going?
雨
作詞・作曲 常田大希
Ame
Lyrics/Composition by Daiki Tsuneta
誰も知らない名もない今を駆けて行くの
Running through this nameless 'now'
雨に霞き消えて手を伸ばして
Fading away in the rain, reaching out my hand
君を知りたい声にならない臆病な朝も
I want to know you, even on cowardly mornings
たとえ何度書き換えようと思う
No matter how many times I think of rewriting it
へその緒がパチンと切られたその時
When the umbilical cord was snapped
世界とはぐれてしまったみたいだ
It felt like I got separated from the world
目に映る景色が悲しく笑うなら
If the scenery in my eyes smiles sadly
恐れず瞼を閉じてごらん
Try closing your eyelids without fear
さぁ皆さんこちらへと底なしの方へさぁ
Come everyone, towards the bottomless depths
踵打ち鳴らせと心踊る方へさぁ
Click your heels towards where your heart dances
蜃気楼に飛び乗って逆さまな世界乗りこなして
Jump on a mirage and master the upside-down world
止まない愛を知りたいと願うおまじない
A spell to wish to know unending love
時を超えて逆らう夜まで
Crossing time until the night we defy
君を知りたい何一つ見逃さぬように
I want to know you, so I don't miss a thing
時は誰も待ってくれないの
Time waits for no one
残酷な運命が抗えぬ宿命が
Cruel fate, irresistible destiny
考える間もなく押し寄せ砂嵐で
Rushing in like a sandstorm without time to think
前が見えなくたって君を信じてみたいの
Even if I can't see, I want to believe in you
恐れずに一歩踏み出したら
If you take a step without fear
さぁ皆さんこちらへと底なしの方へさぁ
Come everyone, towards the bottomless depths
踵打ち鳴らせと心踊る方へさぁ
Click your heels towards where your heart dances
さぁ皆さんこちらへと底なしの方へさぁ
Come everyone, towards the bottomless depths
踵打ち鳴らせと心踊る方へさぁ
Click your heels towards where your heart dances
空飛ぶ鯨に飛び乗って
Jump on a flying whale
逆さまな世界踊り尽くせ
and dance through the upside-down world
誰も知らない名もない今を駆けて行くの
Running through this nameless 'now'
あの三日月消えても伸ばして
Even if that crescent moon disappears, reach out
ラルラライ 君を知りたい 声にならない臆病な
Ral-lu-ra-lai, I want to know you, wordless and cowardly
Mermaid たとえ何度...
Mermaid, no matter how many times...
...生まれ変わろうとも
...I am reborn
夢ならば覚めないで
If it's a dream, don't wake me up
現実なんてさ 身も蓋もないから
Because reality is so blunt
時は誰も待ってくれないなら
Because time waits for no one
聞いてくれてありがとうございます。
Thank you for listening.
はあ、どうだったかな。
Haa, how was it?
「人魚姫」、「クジラ」、「YOU」...
I sang "Mermaid", "Kujira", "YOU"...
...歌わせていただいたんですが、
...but,
これには実はテーマがありまして、
there's actually a theme to this,
何のテーマでしょう。
What could the theme be?
「人魚姫」、「クジラ」、「YOU」、
"Mermaid", "Kujira", "YOU",
そしてこのステージを見てもらったら...
And if you look at this stage,
...わかるかなと思うんですが、
I think you'll understand, but...
テーマは「海」の曲を歌わせていただきました！
The theme was songs about the "sea"!
いや見て、このステージ！すごいよね！
Look at this stage! It's amazing, isn't it?
スタッフさんたちが頑張って制作してくださりまして、
The staff worked hard to create it,
このスクリーンもね、全面にこれ繋がってて、すごいね！
And this screen, it's connected all the way around, it's incredible!
いや、また後でね見返してほしいんだけど、
I want you to look back at it later, but
この全面スクリーンで、
on this panoramic screen,
動画ね、流していただいたりしながら、
they're playing videos and stuff,
この後ろで泳いどる、クジラかな？
And swimming behind me, is that a whale?
イルカかな？なんだろうね、
Or a dolphin? I wonder what it is,
魚たちがね、泳いでいたり、
Fish are swimming around,
あとは、ヒトデとか、
and there are starfish,
これなんだろうね、ホタテかな？
What's this, a scallop?
とか、サンゴかな？とかね、
and maybe coral? and things like that,
あ、見やすい。
Ah, it's easy to see.
とかね、置いてくださって。
they've placed things like that.
ここは深海、海の中を表現しております。
This represents the deep sea, the inside of the ocean.
みんな息は続いてるかな？大丈夫かな？
Is everyone still breathing? Are you okay?
海の中今ライブやってるけど大丈夫かな？
We're doing a live show underwater right now, but are you okay?
実はこのね、テーマの「海」というのも、
Actually, this "sea" theme is
まあ重大告知にちょっと関係してくると言いますか、
somewhat related to the major announcement,
なにかね、気になるね！
What could it be? I'm curious!
まあ何かなとわくわくしながら、この後も楽しんでいただきたいなと思います！
I hope you'll enjoy the rest of the show while wondering what it is!
ここからは、わための大好きな...
From here, I'm going to sing a song
...ポルノグラフィティさんの曲を歌っていこうと思います。
by one of my favorites, Porno Graffitti.
聞いてください。
Please listen.
私は私とはぐれるわけにはいかないから
Because I cannot afford to lose sight of who I am,
いつかまた会いましょう
let's meet again someday
その日までサヨナラ恋心よ
Until that day, goodbye to my feelings of love
サウダージ
Saudade
嘘をつくぐらいなら何も話してくれなくていい
If you're going to lie, I'd rather you say nothing at all
あなたは去っていくの それだけは分かっているから
You're leaving, I know that much at least
見つめ合った私は可愛い女じゃなかったね
I wasn't a "cute girl" as we looked into each other's eyes, was I?
せめて最後は笑顔で飾らせて
At least let me adorn the end with a smile
涙が悲しみを溶かして...
If tears are meant to dissolve sadness...
...溢れるものだとしたら
...and overflow,
その雫ももう一度飲み干してしまいたい
I'd want to drink down those droplets once more
凛とした痛み胸に留まり続ける限り
As long as this dignified pain remains in my chest,
あなたを忘れずにいられるでしょう
I'll be able to stay without forgetting you
許してね恋心よ 甘い夢は波にさらわれたの
Forgive me, my feelings of love, the sweet dream was swept away
いつかまた会いましょう その日までサヨナラ恋心よ
Let's meet again someday, until that day, goodbye to my feelings of love
時を重ねるごとに一つずつあなたを知っていって
With every passing moment, I got to know you bit by bit
さらに時を重ねて一つずつわからなくなって
And as more time passed, one by one I understood you less
愛が消えていくのを夕日に例えてみたりして
I tried comparing the fading of love to the setting sun
そこに確かに残るサウダージ
There, saudade certainly remains
想いを紡いだ言葉まで影を背負わすのならば
If you're going to cast shadows on the words that spun my thoughts,
海の底で物言わぬ貝になりたい
I want to become a silent shell at the bottom of the sea
誰にも邪魔をされずに海に帰れたらいいのに
I wish I could return to the sea without being disturbed
あなたを独り占め...
To have you all to myself...
サウダージ
Saudade
...言わせて
...let me say it.
諦めて 恋心よ
Give up, oh my loving heart.
青い期待は 私を切り裂くだけ
These naive expectations only tear me apart.
あの人に 伝えて
Tell that person...
淋しい 大丈夫 淋しい
I'm lonely. It's okay. I'm lonely.
繰り返される よくある話
A common story repeating itself over and over.
出会いと別れ 泣くも笑うも
Meetings and partings, crying and laughing.
好きも嫌いも
Loving and hating.
許してね 恋心よ
Forgive me, oh my loving heart.
甘い夢は 波にさらわれたの
My sweet dreams were swept away by the waves.
いつかまた 会いましょう
Let's meet again someday.
その日まで さよなら 恋心よ
Until that day, goodbye, oh my loving heart.
あなたの側では 永遠を
By your side, I felt eternity...
確かに感じたから
...so clearly.
夜空を焦がして
Scorching the night sky,
私は生きたわ 恋心と
I lived on with my loving heart.
Zombies are standing out
作詞：新藤晴一　作曲：岡野昭仁
Lyrics: Haruichi Shindo / Composition: Akihito Okano
醒めきったCrazy town
In this completely cooled-down crazy town.
現実と呼ぶ名のバレットに
By the bullet named "Reality",
撃ち抜かれた
I was shot through.
Zombies are crying out
蠢いているMy hell
My hell is squirming.
何を探し 彷徨っているの
What am I searching for as I wander?
赤く爛れた繊細な器官
Delicate organs, red and inflamed.
感情を喪失した
Having lost all emotion,
焦点の合わない夢
A dream out of focus.
この街をベッタリと覆い尽くす
Completely covering this town,
無感覚と無更新が
Insensibility and lack of renewal...
混じる大気汚染
...mix into the air pollution.
Come out underground
安らぎは与えられない
Peace will not be granted.
Zombies are starving out
渇望してる暴走
Craving a rampage.
脳裏に残ってる おぼろげな記憶がまた
The faint memories remaining in my mind again...
Zombies are staring out
蘇るアフロディーテ
Aphrodite is resurrected.
ここじゃ誰も眠ってはならぬ
No one must sleep here.
熱い血が流れてた時のことを
About the time when hot blood flowed.
思い出そうとしても頭が割れそうに痛む
Even if I try to remember, my head hurts as if it's splitting.
ただ歩いているけど無目的で
Just walking aimlessly,
ありついたご馳走には悪臭が漂った
The feast I finally found stank of a foul odor.
Come out underground
死体を見晒し続けて
Continuing to expose the corpse.
Zombies are crying
Oh... 冷めきった Crazy
Oh... a completely chilled-out crazy
現実と言われる名の 弾丸(バレット)に撃ち抜かれた
Shot through by a bullet known as reality
Zombies are crying
Oh... 蠢いている My head
Oh... squirming inside my head
何を捜し彷徨っているの
What am I searching for, wandering about?
清らかな水をくれ 焼け付くこの喉に
Give me pure water for this burning throat
声が枯れるほどに叫んでいるのだけど
Though I'm screaming until my voice runs dry
Zombies are crying
Oh... 慈悲なき闇で
Oh... in the merciless darkness
死して生きるとはの転生
The reincarnation of living after death
立ち上がれ Living dead
Stand up, living dead
Zombies are remember me
Zombies, remember me
夢見たいよ
I want to see a dream
静けさが染み込むようで 息を止めた午前5時
The silence sinks in, and I hold my breath at 5 AM
非常階段で爪を噛む 明日はどっちだ The Day
Biting my nails on the fire escape, which way is tomorrow, The Day?
THE DAY
作詞・作曲 新藤晴一
Lyrics/Composition: Haruichi Shindo
決して明けない夜も 降り続けて止まない雨も
Even nights that never end, and rain that falls without stopping
このろくでもない世界にはあるんだよ
They exist in this good-for-nothing world
少しも変ではないの 泥濘みに足を取られてる
It's not strange at all, having your feet caught in the mud
あなたを責めているわけじゃないんだよ
I'm not blaming you for it
独り 空想に遊ぶ
Playing in fantasies alone
そこで思い描いたことまで 恥じるのかい？
Do you even feel ashamed of what you imagined there?
絡み合う 迷宮 迷宮 それでも行くと言うの？
An entangling labyrinth, a labyrinth, yet you say you'll go?
小さき旅人が奏でる 始まりの鐘の音
A tiny traveler plays the bell of beginnings
行く当ても 茫々 茫々 本当は怖いんじゃないの？
No destination, just vagueness, vagueness, aren't you actually scared?
踏み出すその一歩一歩が 変えてゆく奇跡
Every step you take forward is a miracle that changes things
さあ 立て The Day
Now, stand up, The Day
分かり合えない奴も 分かったようなふりした奴も
Those you can't understand, and those who pretend to understand
このろくでもない世界にはいるんだよ
They are in this good-for-nothing world
ここは地獄じゃなくて まして天国のはずもなく
This isn't hell, and certainly isn't meant to be heaven either
ちょうどその真ん中のような場所なんだ
It's a place just right in the middle
遊ぼう 占いのカード
Let's play with the tarot cards
風が巻き上げた意味なら 知ってるんだろう
You probably know the meaning the wind blew up
絡み合う 迷宮 迷宮 それでも行くと言うの？
An entangling labyrinth, a labyrinth, yet you say you'll go?
小さき旅人が奏でる 始まりの鐘の音
A tiny traveler plays the bell of beginnings
行く当ても 茫々 茫々 本当は怖いんじゃないの？
No destination, just vagueness, vagueness, aren't you actually scared?
踏み出すその一歩一歩が 変えてゆく奇跡
Every step you take forward is a miracle that changes things
さあ 立て The Day
Now, stand up, The Day
その目で見えたものだけ 信じていたいけれど
I want to believe only in what I saw with these eyes, but...
影に怯えては
If you are frightened by the shadows...
悪い予感が本当に化ける
Bad premonitions will truly transform
Cry more...
果てしないリアルサバイバー
Boundless real survivor
足を引っ張り合う
Pulling each other down
生き残ったものが勝者で
The survivor is the winner
フェアなどは幻想
And fairness is an illusion
忍び寄るシュガーハンター
The creeping sugar hunter
誘うのはデカダンス
Inviting us to decadence
二畳の階段、鉄爪を研ぐ
On a two-mat staircase, sharpening iron claws
明日はどっちだ 斬前
Which way is tomorrow? Zan-zen
わぁー、聴いてくれてありがとうございました！
Waa, thank you so much for listening!
配信のタイトルにもさせていただきました、THE DAY でしたー。
That was "THE DAY," which I also used as the title for this stream.
これまで「Happy Day to You」、お祝いの曲から「夢見る羊」...
Up until now, from the celebratory "Happy Day to You," to "Yumemiru Hitsuji"...
「夢を叶える準備はいいですか？ オッケー」という曲、そして海の曲...
to the song "Are you ready to make your dreams come true? OK!", and the sea songs...
「STAGE」、このステージからの、ポルノグラフィティさんの曲...
to "STAGE," and from this stage, a song by Porno Graffitti...
これは一体どういうことなのか分かるかな？
I wonder if you can tell what this all means?
分かるかな？ 何だろうなー。
Do you know? I wonder what it is.
今からめちゃくちゃすごい重大告知をしようかなと思います。
I'm about to make a truly incredible major announcement.
これまでの曲も、今から告知する内容にちなんだテーマとなっているんですが...
The songs so far have been based on the theme of what I'm about to announce...
この度、わための夢が一つ叶いました！
This time, one of Watame's dreams has come true!
なんと、ポルノグラフィティのお二人に新曲を制作していただきました！
Unbelievably, the two members of Porno Graffitti have produced a new song for me!
お二人が二人揃って楽曲提供をするということは初めてらしいんだよね。
Apparently, it's the first time they've provided a song together like this.
これはすごいことだと思うんだけど、どうかな？
I think this is something amazing, don't you?
そしてなんと、今日はお二人からメッセージもいただいております。
And incredibly, I have messages from the two of them today.
では、読みます。
Well then, I'll read them.
角巻さんの明るく、愛されるキャラクターをイメージして曲を作りました。
We created the song with Watame-san's bright and beloved character in mind.
ファンの皆さんと一緒に歌い、盛り上がってくれたら嬉しいです。
We would be happy if you sing along and get excited with the fans.
そして、お誕生日おめでとうございます！ 岡野昭仁
And, happy birthday! - Akihito Okano
昭仁さんありがとうございます！ディスパッチャーズも応援しております！
Thank you, Akihito-san! I'm also supporting DISPATCHERS!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！この曲をどんな風に表現してもらえるか楽しみにしています。
Happy birthday! I'm looking forward to seeing how you express this song.
新藤晴一
Haruichi Shindo
晴一さんもありがとうございます！ミュージカル応援しております！
Thank you, Haruichi-san! I'm supporting the musical!
この文字数の差とかも「Love-up!」というファンクラブに入ってる人は分かると思うんですけど...
Those in the "Love-up!" fan club will probably understand the difference in text length...
大体岡野昭仁さんの方が文字の量が多くて、晴一さんの方が少ないみたいな...
Usually Akihito Okano-san's messages are longer, and Shindo-san's are shorter...
みんなのおかげで、こうしてまた一つ夢を叶えることができました。
Thanks to everyone, I was able to make another dream come true like this.
そして曲名が「FINS」という曲名になっております。
And the song title is "FINS."
で...
And...
ま、ちょっと曲をね、
Well, I think you'll understand
聴いていただいたら分かるかなと思うんですけど
once you've heard the song.
ま、ちょっと海にちなんだというか
Well, it's sort of themed after the sea.
まあ、ちょっと頑張ろうかなと思えるような、
A song that makes you think, "I'll try my best,"
そんなさわやかで、ちょっと頑張ってみよう、元気になれるような
that's refreshing and makes you feel energetic...
わためと一緒に頑張ろうね、みたいな。
...like, "Let's do our best with Watame."
なんかそんな曲になっておりますので
It's that kind of song.
ぜひ、聴いてほしいなと思います
I'd really like you to listen to it.
心を込めて歌います
I'll sing it with all my heart.
それでは聴いてください
Please listen to...
Fins
Every emotions has a fin
It takes me to beautiful places
心泳ぐ
Swimming in my heart,
感情たちは
the emotions
まるで銀の渦の鰯
Are like sardines in a silver whirlpool
未だ形 定まらずに
Still without a fixed form,
水に跳ねる光の粒を追って
Chasing particles of light bouncing on the water
それじゃ気まま過ぎると
Will you blame me,
僕を責めるかい？
for being too carefree?
まるで予測不能
Completely unpredictable,
I don't know where to go?
いつかは大きなソウルになるかな
I wonder if I'll become a big soul someday
僕という輪郭を
The outline of myself,
強く強く描くの
I'm drawing strongly, so strongly
水面を飛び出し
Leaping from the surface,
翻ってみせる
I'll show you my flight
豪快な水飛沫
With a grand splash,
今日の涙と共に空高くへ
soaring high into the sky with today's tears
いつも迷う感情たちが
Emotions that are always lost
隠している意志をただ聞き取って
Simply listening to the hidden will
それが導く先が 理想と違っても
Even if where it leads is different from the ideal
遠く彼方であるならいい
As long as it's far, far away
巨大なハリケーン
A giant hurricane,
不穏な未来は
the ominous future
ギラついた目で睨む
Staring with glinting eyes,
怯えながらそれでも
even while trembling
そいつとダンスを踊るということさ
It means dancing with it
簡単じゃないけれど
It's not easy, but
手を差し出し優雅に誘うマナー
reaching out a hand, manners of elegant invitation
生きてく理由に思いを巡らせ
Pondering the reasons for living
生まれたからだと断言してみる
I'll try asserting it's because I was born
それは深い海流のようなフィロソフィ
It's a philosophy like a deep ocean current
僕は漂流してるばかりじゃないんだ
I'm not just drifting away
Every emotions has a fin
It takes me to beautiful places
いつかは大きなソウルになるかな
I wonder if I'll become a big soul someday
僕という輪郭を
The outline of myself,
強く強く描くの
I'm drawing strongly, so strongly
水面を飛び出し
Leaping from the surface,
翻ってみせる
I'll show you my flight
豪快な水飛沫
With a grand splash,
今日の涙と共に空高くへ
soaring high into the sky with today's tears
Every emotions has a fin
It takes me to beautiful places
いつか！
Someday!
一緒に！
Together!
この曲を武道館で歌いましょう！
Let's sing this song at the Budokan!
みんなのおかげで、また一つ夢を叶えることができました！
Thanks to everyone, I was able to make another dream come true!
いつも本当に...
Always truly...
みんな、ありがとうー！
Everyone, thank you!
これからもよろしくー！
Please continue to support me!
ライブ見てくれてありがとうございましたー！
Thank you for watching the live!
『Fins』、どうだったでしょうか？
How did you like "Fins"?
デビュー当時からずっと、尊敬してる、
I've been saying since my debut that the artists
応援してるアーティストさんといえば、ポルノグラフィティさんだと言い続けていたので...
I respect and support the most are Porno Graffitti...
そのお二人から楽曲提供していただけたこと、
Getting a song provided by the two of them
今でも本当に夢のように感じます。
still feels like a dream even now.
でも、このお知らせをみんなに届けることができて、
But I'm truly happy from the bottom of my heart
本当に心から嬉しく思います。
that I could share this announcement with everyone.
そんな、角巻わため新オリジナル曲『Fins』が、
Tsunomaki Watame's new original song "Fins" will be
このあと24時から各種音楽配信サービスにて、配信開始となります！
available on various music streaming services starting at midnight!
そして、22時...このあと、夜10時からは『Fins』のムービーが、
And at 22:00... later tonight at 10 PM, the "Fins" movie
わためぇチャンネルにて、投稿されますので、ぜひ見てください！
will be posted on Watame-channel, so please check it out!
そして、角巻わため誕生日記念グッズが、今年も出ます！
Also, Tsunomaki Watame birthday memorial goods are coming out again this year!
アクリルジオラマスタンド、わためぇと手袋、ステッカー、
There are four types: acrylic diorama stand, "Watame-and-Gloves," stickers,
わためぇとプロフィールカードドドの4種類になっております。
and "Watame-and-Profile Card-dodo."
グッズのフルセットをご購入いただいた方には、
For those who purchase the full set of goods,
特典ボイスと、えー、ポストカードが付いてきます。
a bonus voice and, uh, a postcard will be included.
今回も数量限定なしで、えー、
This time as well, there's no quantity limit,
直筆サイン&メッセージを書かせていただきますので、よろしくお願いします。
and I'll be writing hand-signed autographs and messages, so please look forward to it.
ふーみママ描き下ろしの、アクリルジオラマスタンドは、
The acrylic diorama stand illustrated by Fumi-mama
ライブをテーマにしていて、わためぇバンドなど、
is themed after the live performance, and some parts
取り外しが可能になっているものもありますので、配置を好きに入れ替えることができたりします。
like the "Watame Band" are removable, so you can rearrange the layout however you like.
さらに、わためぇと手袋。こちらのグッズ、
Furthermore, "Watame-and-Gloves." I think these goods
届くのがまた、寒くなってきた頃になるかなと思うので、あったかモコモコグッズをご用意しました。
will arrive around the time it starts getting cold again, so I've prepared some warm and fluffy items.
表は、羊のような白色。内側はピンク。
The outside is white like a sheep. The inside is pink.
今回は、オーラわためぇのタグが付いています。
This time, it comes with an "Aura Watame" tag.
そして、ステッカー。こちらは、わため将軍や、わたおじなど、
And stickers. These include four types of Watame like
4種類のわためプラス、わためぇとのシールになっております。
Watame Shogun and Wata-oji, plus a "Watame-and-You" sticker.
いつでも視界に入るように、パソコンや、
I hope you'll stick them on your computer or
好きなところに、貼ってほしいなと、思います。
anywhere you like so they're always in sight.
そしてそして！わためぇとプロフィールカードドド！
And next! "Watame-and-Profile Card-dodo!"
自分の名前や、趣味などが書き込めるようになっているので、写真を撮って、SNSに投稿するなり...
You can write your own name and hobbies, so you can take a picture and post it on SNS...
イベントとかで、わためぇと同士、カード交換をしても、
I thought it might be fun to exchange cards with
楽しいかも、と思って、作らせていただきました。自由に使ってください。
fellow "Watamates" at events, so I made this. Please use it freely.
この4点のグッズをセットで、ご購入いただいた方には、撮り下ろし特典ボイスと、
For those who purchase these four items as a set, you'll receive
わための直筆サイン&メッセージ入りポストカードが付いてきます。
a newly recorded bonus voice and a postcard with Watame's hand-signed autograph and message.
枚数制限なんと、えー、ございません。
There is no limit on the number of copies.
ので、遠慮なく、たくさん、ゲットしてほしいなと、思います。
So please don't hesitate to get as many as you want.
それぞれ単品販売も、ありますので、いいなと思うものがあったら、
Individual items are also for sale, so if there's
後悔しないように、ぜひ手に入れてください。
anything you like, please make sure to get it so you don't regret it later.
最後に！このあと、10時15分から、メン限アンコールライブを3Dで行いますので、
Lastly! After this, starting at 10:15 PM, there will be a members-only encore live in 3D, so
まだまだ音楽を一緒に、楽しみてぇ、まだまだいけるぜー！
for those who want to keep enjoying music together and can still go on!
という方は、ぜひメンバーシップに、入って、ちょっとお待ちいただければと、思います。
If that's you, please join the membership and wait for a bit.
では、わためは準備をしてきますので、『Fins』のムービーを見て、
Now, I'm going to go get ready, so please watch
グッズを買って、待っててください！
the "Fins" movie, buy some goods, and wait for me!
またあとでね！本当に、みんな、いつもありがとう！
See you later! Truly, thank you all for everything!
みんな、いつもありがとう！
Everyone, thank you for everything!
これからも一緒に、夢を叶えていこうね！
Let's continue to make our dreams come true together!
I ❤️ わためいと　わため
I ❤️ Watamate - Watame